Guide to the Tennesse Williams Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Works, 1945-1982 11 linear ft.
  - Subseries II.1: Plays and Screenplays, 1937-1982
    - The Milk Train Doesn't Stop Here Anymore, [n.p.], 1962-1963, (Spoleto production: Notes for revision, program, photographs [acq 599624]; Programs for 1963 New York production) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - The Milk Train Doesn't Stop Here Anymore, New York, August - September 1963, (Claire Luce material: Script revised August 13, 1963 inscribed to Luce by Williams, notes, letters, clippings, programs [acq 400780C]) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - The Milk Train Doesn't Stop Here Anymore, [n.p.], 1962-1981, (3 folders of annotated script pages and script, Mimeographed Playing Version script with letter dated January 7, 1965, clippings, reviews, publicity) (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
    - Moony's Kid Don't Cry, [n.p.], 1958, (30 p. t.ms.s., mimeographed [acq 255017]) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Night of the Iguana, [n.p.], 1961-1981, (1 folder of annotated script pages) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Night of the Iguana, [New York], 1961-1964, (t.ms.s, Final and approved New York playing version; inscribed to George Williams; mimeographed, 1962 Foreign Press Award [acq 255015]; Pressbook [acq 278111]) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Night of the Iguana, [n.p.], 1976, (2 copies of French version by Eudes de Saint-Simon. 1 copy inscribed by Williams to Gill 1976) (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
    - Night of the Iguana, [v.p.], 1961-1981, (Congratulatory telegrams (1961), programs, poster, clippings) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Notebook of Trigorin, [n.p.], 1981, (Autograph script pages, program, letters) (Box 14, Folder 2)
      [Free adaptation of Anton Chekhov's The Sea Gull]
    - Now and at the Hour of Our Death, [n.p.], [1969], (23 pp. t.ms., unpublished, with autograph corrections [acq 290732 in memory of Charles W. Mixer]) (Box 14, Folder 3)
      [On microfilm. Master negative number 2000-2031]
    - One-Arm, [n.p.], December 1967, (Annotated mimeographed first draft) (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - One-Arm, [n.p.], 1969, 1979, (Photocopied screenplay August 1, 1969, clipping May 18, 1979) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Orpheus Descending; or, The Memory of an Orchard, [n.p.], Sept. 1953, (109 pp. t.ms. and microfilm [acq 702814]) (Box 14, Folder 6)
      [On microfilm. Master negative number 93-2000-1
      See also Battle of Angels and The Fugitive Kind]
    - Orpheus Descending, [v.p.], 1957-1989, (t.ms. and microfilm draft revisions with corrections, letters [acq. 487-490-7.1.88], programs) (Box 14, Folder 7)
      [See also Battle of Angels and The Fugitive Kind]
    - Orpheus Descending, [n.p.], 1957-1982, (Clippings, programs (Greek version)) (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Out Cry, [n.p.], 1971-1982, ( 3 set designs by Jo Mielziner 1973, letters, clippings) (Box 15, Folder 1)
      [See also Two Character Play]
    - Period of Adjustment, [n.p.], 1960-1962, (Annotated typed script pages, set design by Jo Mielziner 1960 [acq. 297, 1986], clippings, reviews, Screen Writers' Annual Award 1962 [Key West]; programs, pressbook [acq 2778102]) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Players and the Play, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Annotated television play script pages) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Plenty of Zip, [n.p.], [n.d.], (8 p. typescript mimeograph, fragment with corrections by the author) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Portrait of a Madonna, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 Program) (Box 15, Folder 5)
      [Part of evening of plays entitled Triple Play]
    - Purification, [n.p.], 1965-1975, (Letters, clippings) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Quiet Voices, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Annotated typed script pages) (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Rectangle with Hooks or Mint and Hall, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Annotated typed script pages) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Red Devil Battery Sign: A Work for the Presidential Theater, London, Sept. 1976, (116 p. Typescript mimeograph, revised London version [Lyle Leverich, 3/6/90]) (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Red Devil Battery Sign, [n.p.], 1975-1981, (Typed script pages, 2 mimeographed scripts--Post Vancouver draft June 25, 1981 and August 28, 1981, clippings, casting list, reviews, photographs) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Remarkable Rooming House of Mme. Le Monde, [n.p.], 1984, (Pamphlet published by Albondoconi Press) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone, [v.p.], 1960, (Annotated typed script pages, mimeographed first draft by Gavin Lambert, June 4, 1960 [Key West]; Notes [acq 487/490-7.1.88] ) (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone, [n.p.], 1960, (Mimeographed screenplay revised November 28, 1960 [Key West]; Pressbook [acq 278103]) (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - The Rose Tattoo, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Annotated t.ms., Outline for early draft "The Eclipse of May 29, 1919," draft revisions [acq 487-1986]) (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - The Rose Tattoo, [n.p.], 1951, (Notes by Williams, set design by Boris Aronson [acq. 486, July 1986], production notes, Paul Bigelow's script, program signed by cast [acq 487-1986]) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - The Rose Tattoo, [v.p.], 1951-1995, (Press release, playbills) (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - The Rose Tattoo, [n.p.], 1951-1977, (Clippings, reviews, program, posters, Tony medal, scrapbook for 1963 Czech production) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - A Sentimental Conclusion, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Annotated typed script pages) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - The Seven Descents of Myrtle, [n.p.], 1968-1972, (1 Program, review) (Box 16, Folder 5)
      [See also Kingdom of Earth]
    - Skylight or Broken Glass in the Morning, [n. p.], [n.d.], (a. ts., [487/490-7.1.88]) (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Short Short, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Annotated typed script) (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Small Craft Warnings, [n.p.], 1971-1972, (Annotated mimeographed script pages, programs, letters, clippings, articles) (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Something Cloudy, Something Clear, [n.p.], 1980-1981, (Annotated typed script pages, mimeograhed first draft revised March 26, 1980, clippings) (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
    - Stairs to the Roof, [n.p.], February 26, 1947, (1 Program) (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Steps Must Be Gentle [play], [n.p.], 1980, (1 Galley proof of play about Hart Crane) (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Stopped Rocking, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a. ts. mimeograph) (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Stopped Rocking, Santa MonicaCalifornia, [n.d.], (1 mimeographed ts screenplay) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Stopped Rocking, [n.p.], 1979-1981, (2 mimeographed first draft screenplays, March 19, 1979; letters) (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
    - A Streetcar Named Desire, New York, [1947], (139 pp. t.ms., 1 t.l.s. (Jo Mielziner's copy dated April 12, 1947 with letter from Williams to Mielziner laid in) [acp 550520E]) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - A Streetcar Named Desire, [v.p.], 1947 & [n.d.], (Williams' script inscribed to Josephine Healey, program, clipping, 2 transfers from the streetcar named Desire [Friends 55052E]) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - A Streetcar Named Desire, [n.p.], 1972-1982, (1 Folder of flyers, programs, clippings, reviews) (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Suddenly Last Summer, [n.p.], ca. 1958, (19 pp. t.ms., fragments of play, annotated, title inscribed on p. 1 :'Cabeza de Lobo' or 'A Las Cinco de la Tarde' [487/490-7.1.88], pressbook [278109]) (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Suddenly Last Summer, [n.p.], 1958-1970s, (1 folder of annotated typed script pages, poster, program, clippings) (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Summer and Smoke, Rome and New York, March 1947, 1948, (ca. 150 pp. t.ms.s., inscribed by Williams to Josephine Healy on the title-page [acq Friends 55052E]) (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Summer and Smoke, [n.p.], [n.d.], (68 pp. t.ms.s., mimeographed script used in Dallas first production [acq 292673, memory of Charles W. Mixer]) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Summer and Smoke, New York, 6 Oct. 1948, (110 pp. t.ms.s., prompt copy, signed by Williams and actor Margaret Phillips in slipcase [Archon of Colophon in memory of Charles W. Mixer 1974, 304734]; program, pressbook [acq 178105]) (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Summer and Smoke, [n.p.], 1949-1982, (1 folder of mimeographed script, mimeographed screenplay (June 22, 1959), clippings, programs, opera libretto) (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Sweet Bird of Youth, New York, 1956-1959, (1 signed 1956 program [acq 304755]; t.ms., mimeographed 1959 [acq 344527]) (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Sweet Bird of Youth, [n.p.], 1958, (Set designs, watercolor on paper and photostats [acq 487-2.3.88]) (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Sweet Bird of Youth, New York, 1959, 1970s, (Clare Luce's mimeographed script 1959 [Archons of Colophon in memory of Charles W. Mixer 4029720]; 2 programs, 1 pressbook [acq 278101]) (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Sweet Bird of Youth, [n.p.], 1956-1979, (1 folder of annotated typed script pages, posters, financial report, clippings) (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Tent Worms, [n.p.], 1979, (109 pp. t.ms., annotated First Draft, May-August, 1979 based on the short story [acq 9430-08,2.3.88].) (Box 18, Folder 8)
      See also Gideon's Point and In Masks Outrageous and Austere]
    - This is (an entertainment), Key West, Jan. 1974, (80 pp. mimeograph ts. first draft [Lyle Leverich copy]) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - This Is, [n.p.], 1975-1978, (Annotated mimeographed script October 11, 1975, revised April 1978) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - This Property is Condemned, [n.p.], [n.d.] & 1981, (1 mimeographed teleplay [acq 255017]; press release, clipping, flyer) (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Tiger Tail, New York, [n.d.] & May 1977, (75 pp. annotated t. ms. draft, mimeographed first typed version; Director's copy- signed by Gary Tucker [acq 490 (Mixer), 12/14/89]) (Box 19, Folder 4)
      [See also Baby Doll and Twenty Seven Wagons Full of Cotton]
    - Tiger Tail, New YorkAtlanta, March 1978, September 1979, (2 mimeographed director's scripts: March 1978 and Final revision September 1979, Atlanta Georgia Alliance Theater [acq 490 (Mixer)-12/14/89]) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Tiger Tail, [n.p.], 1977-1979, (Mimeographed Atlanta Alliance Theatre stage manager's March 1978 script, letters, clippings, ads, programs) (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Twenty Seven Wagons Full of Cotton, [n.p.], 1972, (1 Clipping) (Box 19, Folder 7)
      [See also Baby Doll and Tiger Tail]
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Mimeographed script) (Box 19, Folder 8)
      [See also Out Cry]
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], 1966, (1 Annotated mimeographed script revised October 18, 1966 ) (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Two Character Play, New York, 1966, (4 mimeographed scripts revised October 18, 1966) (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], 1967, (1 Mimeographed script January 20, 1967 with typed author's preface. ) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], 1967, (Mimeographed script August 1967) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Mimeographed London script ) (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], 1970, (Mimeographed script revised February 1970) (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], 1960s-1982, (1 folder of annotated script pages, letters, clippings) (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], [n.d], (1 Script, Lyle Leverich copy [acq 297, 3/6/90]) (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Vieux Carre, New York, May 1977, (90 pp., mimeographed script, Lyle Leverich copy [acq 297, 3/6/90]) (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Vieux Carre, [n.p.], 1973-1982, (1 folder of annotated script pages, mimeographed second draft November 1973, programs, clippings) (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Virgo, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder of annotated script pages) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Will Mr. Merriwether Return From Memphis?, [n.p.], 1969-1980, (1 folder of mimeographed script revised September 1969, clipping, poster) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - You Touched Me, [n.p.], Nov. 1942, (116 pp. t.ms., carbon copy, "Revised Version 'B"; adapted from a short story by D. H. Lawrence [acq 702812]) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - You Touched Me, [n.p.], 1945, (1 folder of clippings) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Combined Plays:, [n.p.], 1958-1982, (3 folders of material on productions of multiple Williams works from The Garden District in 1958 to the 1982 Tennessee Williams: A Celebration at the Williamstown Theatre Festival) (Box 21, Folder 6-8)
    - Dragon Country or Two Plays, [n.p.], n.d., (1 folder of script (9104618)and pages for Confessional and I Can't Imagine Tomorrow) (Box 21, Folder 9)
      [See also Confessional and Small Craft Warnings]
    - Dragon Country or Two Plays, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 folders of mimeographed scripts (9404625) for Confessional and I Can't Imagine Tomorrow) (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - Slapstick Tragedy, [n.p.], 1965, (1 folder of annotated typed script pages, typed and autograph notes, and mimeographed rehearsal version of March 1, 1965 script for The Mutilated and The Gnadiges Fraulein) (Box 22, Folder 3)
      [See also The Gnadiges Fraulein]
    - Three Works for the Lyric Theatre: Now the Cats With Jewelled Claws; The Youthfully Departed; A Cavalier for Milady, [n.p.], [n.d.], (80 pp. ts., Lyle Leverich copy) (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Three Works for the Lyric Theater, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder of annotated mimeograph script of Now the Cats With Jewelled Claws, Youthfully Departed and A Cavalier for Milady) (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Workbooks and draft pages, [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 folders of autograph notebooks, annotated typed script pages, unidentified set design) (Box 22, Folder 6-9)
    - Unidentified draft pages, [n.d.], [n.p.], (Annotated ts.) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Untitled script, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder of mimeographed script about Artur Rimbaud) (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Draft pages from unidentified plays, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder of annotated t. ms.) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.2: Stories & Poetry
    This subseries begins with an alphabetical listing of prose works, followed by poetry, articles, sketches and interviews. There are annotated pages, manuscripts, proofs, publications, book jackets, a videocassette, sketches, sketchpads and clippings.
    - Close Two Shot the Kill, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Annotated ts.) (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Desire and the Black Masseur, [n.p.], April 1946, (Carbon ts. with note from publisher James Laughlin to editor Hubert Creekmore [Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Robert L. Wilbur, 1982]) (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Donsinger Women, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder of annotated typed and mimeographed pages) (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Donsinger Women and Their Handyman Jack, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 Videocassette) (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Grand, [n.p.], 1953, ( 1 carbon copy of first draft) (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "Grand", New York, 1966, (in Esquire, vol. LXVI, No. 5 (November 1966): 136.) (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Happy August Tenth, [n.p.], 1971, (1 Short story published in Antaeus Winter 71) (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Hard Candy, Key West, FL, March 1953, (23 pp. t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Idea of Order in Dry Bone, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Photocopy of t. ms.) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - It Happened A Day the Sun Rose, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 Proof) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Kingdom of Earth, New York, 1948, (12 pp. t.ms. carbon [Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Robert L. Wilbur, 1982]) (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Man in the Overstuffed Chair, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t. ms.) (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - "The Mattress By the Tomato Patch", October 1954, (in The London Magazine, Vol. 1, No. 9 (October 1954)) (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Night Was Full of Hours, New Orleans, revised Key West, 1973 & 1978, (1 t. ms.) (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Old Sweetheart of the Keys, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Photocopy of annotated t. ms.) (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Pieces of My Youth, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Mimeograph of selected early writings) (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Portrait of a Girl in Glass, Santa Monica, CA, ca. [June 1943], (16 pp. t.ms. carbon [acq 702815]) (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Recluse and His Guest, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Mimeographed t. ms.) (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - The Resemblance Between a Violin Case and a Coffin, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photocopy of published version) (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - "The Resemblance Between a Violin Case and a Coffin,", 1950, (in Flair (February 1950)) (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone, n.p., n.d., (96 p. t.ms. carbon copy [acq 702816]) (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified pages, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 annotated t. ms.) (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Bookjackets, publicity, clippings, [n.p.], 1967-1978, (1 folder) (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Poems, [v.p.], 1939-1949, (Arranged in alphabetical order. [Various acquisitions. See folders.]) (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Poems, [n.p.], [n.d.] &1982, (Annotated t. ms., arranged alphabetically by title or first line.) (Box 24, Folder 16)
      [See also Audiotapes]
    - Voices, A Journal of Poetry, [n.p.], 1952, (1 Booklet containing poems by Williams and others) (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - "The Christus of Guadalajara" in Botteghe Oscure, n.p., [1958], () (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.3: Other Works & Related Material
    - Essays, [v.p.], 1979, 1982, (2 t.ms. Mes Cahiers Noirs [acq 430, 7.1.88]; Valediction [acq 490 (Mixer), Dec 14, 1989]) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Articles, essays and reviews, [n.p.], 1950-1970s, (1 folder) (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "W. H. Auden: A Few Reminiscences" in The Harvard Advocate Vol CVIII, Nos. 2-3; "What's Next on the Agenda, Mr. Williams?" in Mediterranean Review Vol. 1, N. 2 (Winter 1971): 15-19., v.p., 1971, () (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Art, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Sketches, doodles, drawings, sketchbooks, articles, paintings) (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Appearances, ads, and interviews, [n.p.], 1960s-1970s, (Transcripts, articles, record) (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
      [See also audiotapes]
  - Subseries II.4: Works Based on the Writings of Tennessee Williams
    - Film Treatment, Theater productions, [n.p.], 1980-1982, (Treatment, programs, clippings, ads) (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Grand, [n.p.], May 1979, (1 mimeographed teleplay [Lyle Leverich copy]) (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Migrants, [n.p.], 1972, (1 folder of teleplay adapted by Lanford Wilson, first and second drafts) (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - This Property Is Condemned, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 revised second draft of screenplay adapted by Francis Ford Coppola) (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Subseries II.5: Biography
    - Biographical works, [n.p.], 1972, (Drafts, clippings, reviews and flyers from Memoirs, Letters to Donald Windham and Henry Rasky's documentary Tennessee Williams' South) (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Biographical works, London, 1978, 1981, (2 articles about Letters to Donald Windham: Dotson Rader, "The Private Letters of Tennessee Williams," London Magazine Vol. 18, No. 1(July 1978): 18-28; "The 'Private' Letters of Tennessee Williams," London Magazine, Vol. 20, No. 11-12 (February/March 1981): 80-88.) (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Subseries II.6: Awards & Honors
    - Certificates, plaques, trophies and celebrations, [n.p.], 1950s-1980, (Photographs, clippings, certificates and brochures including the Kennedy Center Honors of 1978 and the Presidential Medal of Freedom Award in 1980) (Box 26, Folder 2-5)
    - Awards and honors, [n.p.], 1982, (1 folder of photographs, clippings, certificates and brochures including honorary doctorate from Harvard University) (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - 70th Birthday Celebration at the Goodman Theater, [n.p.], 1981-1982, (2 folders of brochures, programs, clippings, congratulations and photos) (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
    - Clippings re Williams, [n.p.], 1948-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
  - Subseries II.7: Works About Tennessee Williams
    - By other authors, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder, Alphabetical by author) (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Henry R. Beasley Interpretative Study of the Religious Element in the Work of Tennessee Williams [dissertation], [n.p.], August 1973, (Dissertation, pp. 1-166) (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Henry R. Beasley Interpretative Study of the Religious Element in the Work of Tennessee Williams [dissertation], [n.p.], 1973, (Dissertation, pp. 167-328) (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Tennessee Williams in Tangiers, [n.p.], 1973, (Copies of translation by Paul Bowles of work by Mohamed Choukri) (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Leverich, Lyle Articles, [n.p.], 1978-1979, (1 folder) (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Tennessee and Me, [n.p.], [n.d.], ( Devised by Maxim Mazumda) (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Public and Private Lives of Tennessee Williams, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Biography by Dakin Williams and Shepard Mead) (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
    - Articles about Tennessee Williams, 1953-1981, () (Box 51, Folder 4-6)
    - Articles and poems about Tennessee Williams by unidentified, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 28, Folder 7)
- Series III: Personal
  1941-1983. 2.5 linear ft. This series contains journals, notebooks, address books, date books, messages, financial papers, medical records, post cards, memorabilia, ads, and clippings.
  - Williams, Tennessee Journal, [n.p.], 1941-1942, (a. ms. of second Florida hitchhiking trip and writing journal) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Address Book, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Date books, [n.p.], 1966, 1970, 1977-78, () (Box 29, Folder 3-5)
  - Notes and doodles, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Notes and doodles, n.d., () (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Telephone messages and business cards, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Contracts, [n.p.], 1953-1982, () (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Travel documents, [n.p.], 1962-1963, (12 items: Passport, prescription, and other documents collected by cousin, Stella Adams) (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Financial, [n.p.], 1953-1982, (Statements, invoices, bank records, car records, membership dues) (Box 30, Folder 3-10)
  - Medical records, [n.p.], 1948-1981, (Includes letters on Rose Williams 1949, 1963, 1972) (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Memorabilia and realia, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Menus, ads, flyers, posters, fossils, scarves, glasses, etc.) (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Solicitations, [n.p.], 1963-1983 (Box 31, Folder 2-8)
  - Invitations, [n.p.], 1961-1982, ( ) (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Invitations, [n.p.], 1966-1982 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Post cards and stationery, [n.p.], [n.d.], ( ) (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Societies and Organizations, [n.p.], 1965-1980, (Mailings) (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Magazines, [n.p.], 1962-1982, ( ) (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Magazines, 1935, (1 May 1935 copy of Lovat Dickson's Magazine; Munich art catalog) (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: Theater professionals, [n.p.], 1973-1981, () (Box 32, Folder 5)
    [Arranged alphabetically by subject name]
  - Clippings re Theater by others, [n.p.], 1967-1981, undated, () (Box 32, Folder 6)
    [Arranged chronologically]
  - Programs of plays by others, 1978-1981, () (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Clippings re other artists, [n.p.], 1975-1982, () (Box 32, Folder 7)
    [Arranged alphabetically by subject]
  - Clippings of general interest, [n.p.], 1958-1982, undated, () (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Family: Geneologies, Walter E. Dakin 1882 autograph book, family letters, drawings by Rose Williams, [n.p.], 1971-1977, 1982, ( ) (Box 33, Folder 1-3)
  - Pets, [n.p.], [n.d.], ( ) (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Tennessee Williams Estate, New York, 1989, n.d., (Letter and notes re estate) (Box 33, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Works by Others
  1934-1982. 5 linear ft. This material has been arranged alphabetically by author. It includes manuscripts from friends, from aspiring writers, and those sent by agents. There is a collection of material by and about the writer and friend Carson McCullers, several manuscripts by Williams' companion Robert Carroll, short stories by Williams' brother Dakin, and the poetry of Williams' friend Marion Black Vaccaro.
  - Acuff, Donald Prandles and Prazads, 1971, (1 poem) (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Albee, Edward Seascape, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 Mimeograph of play inscribed to Williams by Albee) (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Alexander, David Erotic Drawings and Lithographs by Regis Dho, 1978, (1 catalog published and inscribed by David Alexander) (Box 52, Folder 5)